（カカシ）あれは…。
That's...
（ナルト）コイツは…。
He's...
マダラだ！
Madara...!
（オビト）穢土転生の術に逆らうとは
実に　アンタらしいな…。
It's just like you... to have defied
the Reanimation Jutsu.
（マダラ）そんなことより
何をもたついている。
More importantly,
what's taking so long?
なんで？　なんで　あっちのマダラが
こっちにいんだよ？
Why? Why is that Madara over here?
マダラ…　あのマダラか？
Madara? You mean that Madara?
こいつも影分身だな。
本体はどこだ？　オビト。
He's a Shadow Clone too...
Where's the real one, Obito?
（八尾）おい　ナルト！
ヤツが　ここにいるってことは…。
Hey, Naruto!
Him being here must mean...
向こうのみんなは　どうした？
What's happened to
everyone over there?
（ビー）ブラザー！
Brother...
あそこか…。
He's over there, eh?
どうしたかって聞いてんだ！
I asked you what happened?!
さあな？　恐らく…。
I'm not sure, but I suspect...
（マダラ）無事ではあるまいな。
... that none of them are doing too well.
for some reason the moon is one size larger tonight
konya no tsuki wa nazeka hitomawari ookikute
it's shining brighter than it usually does
itsumo yori akaruku terasu
I trudge along the road home with my shoulders hunched
senaka wo marumete tobotobo kaeru michi
at any time I will always have a friend
donna toki mo mikata wa iru
without saying a word, it's all right to cry
nani mo iwazu naketara ii ne
once my tears dry, it will all be over
namida ga karetara owari
I need to become stronger...
motto boku ga tsuyoku naranakya
sorrow is the first step towards independence
kanashimi wa jiritsu he no ippo
how many times do I have to get hurt to forget the pain?
nando kizutsukeba itami wo wasureru
when I bleed red, I'm reminded of life
akai chi wo nagaseba inochi wo omoidasu sa
I collapse on the road with my arms and legs spread out
michi ni taore dainoji ni
I look up at the sky and think
sora wo miagete omou
true loneliness is someone without a past
shin no kodoku to wa kako no nai mono
someone who only knows the present
ima shika shiranu mono
Obito and Madara
（綱手）うっ　うぅ…。
Summoning... Jutsu...!
口寄せの術！
Lady Tsunade!
（カツユ）綱手様！
カツユ…　頼みがある。
Katsuyu... Do something for me...
Yes! I'll fuse your body right away...
はい！
すぐに体をくっつけて！
No...
違う！
My lower body can wait.
私の半身は後でいい…。
First...
それより→
Bring the other Kage... to me...
私のところへ　影たちを…。
I... can... still save them.
私なら　まだ…　救える。
Faster than the Curse Mark Chains
can wrap around!
《呪印の鎖を巻くよりも速く…》
I'll return that to you.
It's yours to begin with.
そいつは返す　アンタのだ。
フンッ！
Finally, I can move!
やっと動ける！　サンキューだ　ナルト！
Thanks, Naruto!
Now, it's my turn!
さあ　今度は　俺の番だぜ！
Obito, did you launch
the plan haphazardly
オビト！
八尾も九尾も入れ込む前に→
before you even took in
the Eight and Nine Tails?
中途半端に計画を始めたのか？
He knows about the plan...
《計画を知ってる…
こいつらの関係は？》
What's their relationship?
You were hasty, Obito.
焦ったな　オビト。
Is that also why I was revived
in this form?
俺をこんな姿で復活させたのも
そのせいか？
Well, knowing you...
まあ　お前のことだ
何か考えがあるんだろうが…。
I'm sure you have something in mind.
What have you been up to
all this time?
今まで　何をやっていた。
Where's Nagato?
長門はどうした？
時を見計らい
輪廻天生の術で俺は蘇る。
You were supposed to determine
the appropriate moment
and bring me back to life
with Rinne Rebirth.
That was the agreement.
そういう手はずだったはずだ。
Gedo Art of Rinne Rebirth.
((長門：外道輪廻天生の術！
Nagato's Visual Prowess is the jutsu
that controls life and death.
（小南）長門の瞳力は
生死を司る術。
He is the seventh Pain.
(七人目のペイン))
長門を…
利用しようとしてたのか？
You tried to take advantage
of Nagato?!
He betrayed us.
ヤツは裏切った。
He used the jutsu to revive
the Leaf villagers.
その術で　里の者どもを…。
どいつもこいつも。
I can't depend on any of you.
Well, no matter...
It's still not too late.
まあ　いい。
今からでも遅くはない。
I'll capture the Eight and Nine Tails!
八尾と九尾は俺が捕る！
Dead men shouldn't go around
messing things up!
死んでたヤツが　ひっかき回すな！
うおぉ～！！
Huh?!
《あれ？　爆発しねえ》
It didn't explode?!
Uchiha Reflection.
うちは返し。
（ガイ）くっ！
I'll get the Eight and Nine Tails.
俺が　八尾と九尾をやる。
Obito, you take down those two.
オビト　お前は　コイツらをやれ。
Obito...
オビト　お前に何があったんだ。
What happened to you?
Why would you join up with him?
どうして　あんなヤツと？
((オビト：俺は死んだのか？
Am I... dead?
ここは？
Where am I?
あの世との狭間だ　うちはの者よ。
In between this life and the next...
young Uchiha.
Those eyes!
その眼…
まさか　じいちゃんも　うちはの。
No way, Gramps...
You're an Uchiha too?
Well, perhaps.
さあ　どうだろうな？
《俺を助けてくれたのか？
いや　でも…》
He rescued me?
But wait...
You said we're between
this life and the next.
あの世との狭間って言ったよな。
Where are we?
どこなんだ　ここ？
暗くて　よく見えねえし。
It's dark and I can't see so well.
Anyways, who are you, Gramps?
それに　じいちゃん
いったい誰なんだ？
Heh, don't tell me you're Death!
ヘッ　もしかして
死神じゃねえよな？
The guy who escorts people
to heaven or hell...
天国か地獄に連れていくっていう
あの…。
Nooo!
いや～！！
I don't want to die yet! Help!
まだ死にたくないよ！
助けて～！
I just saw a scythe or something!
鎌とか　チラッて見えたし
絶対　死神だよ！
You're Death for sure!
One especially for the Uchiha!
うちは専門の死神だよ！
Wait! I lived my life under a creed
of helping elderly people in need!
俺…　俺→
困ってるお年寄りを助けるのを
モットーに生きてきました。
Sure, I caused a lot of mischief
and broke a lot of rules....
確かに
悪さも　かなりやったし→
決まりを
破ってばかりだったけど→
But I'm sure my scale tips
on the positive side!
差し引きイーブンってことは
ないと思います。
どうか　地獄だけは…　イテッ。
Please don't take me to hell!
Oww...
The fact that you feel pain
means you're still alive.
痛みを感じるということは
まだ生きているということだ。
However, it's a miracle
that you survived.
しかし　助かったのは
奇跡と言っていい。
よく岩に潰されなかったものだ。
I'm amazed you weren't completely
crushed under those boulders.
It's almost as if you passed
right through them.
まるで　岩をすり抜けたとしか
思えんほどだ。
俺は　どこにいたんだ？
Where did you find me?
In an underground passageway
I had created...
俺の作った地下通路に
倒れていた。
collapsed next to crumbled rock.
崩れた岩の横にな。
といっても　体の半分は
ほぼ潰れてしまっていた。
Still, half your body
had been crushed.
一応
手当てはしておいてやったがな。
I patched you up as best I could.
So you saved me, Gramps.
じいちゃんが助けてくれたのか。
ありがとう。
Thank you.
It's too soon to thank me.
礼を言うのは　まだ早い。
その分の恩は
しっかり返してもらうつもりだ。
I expect you to repay
your debt to me.
After all, helping the elderly
is your motto, right?
年寄りを助けるのが
お前のモットーなのだろう？
Well, yeah.
それは　まあ　そうなんだけど…。
So what do you want me to do?
じゃあ　何すりゃいいんだ？
下の世話とか？
それもいい。
Help you with bathroom stuff?
That would be good.
悪いけど
ずっと　ここにはいられねえよ。
Sorry, but I can't stay here forever!
生きてるって　わかったんなら
俺は　木ノ葉へ帰る。
Now that I know I'm alive,
I'm going back home to
the Hidden Leaf Village!
今は戦争中だ。
There's a war going on.
My Sharingan's finally
awakened...
写輪眼も　やっと開眼したし。
これで　今度は
もっと仲間を守れる。
So now, I'll be able to protect
my comrades even better!
もっと仲間を守るか。
Protect your comrades better, eh...?
なんだよ。
What is it?
With that body...
your life as a shinobi is over.
お前のその体
もう忍としてはやっていけまい。
No, no, no!
いやいやいや！　やっと…
やっと　この眼を手に入れたんだ。
Finally... I finally got this eye!
(今なら　もっとコンビネーションも
うまくいける自信がある！))
I'm confident my attack combinations
will be better now!
《やっぱりな》
I thought so.
((ニオイは完全に消されてる。
The scent has been
completely erased.
かすかな空気の流れや物音で→
We'll have to locate him
by the slightest movement
and noise he makes.
敵の位置を判断するしかないぞ。
ど…　どこだ？
W-Where is he?
Obito, behind you!
オビト　後ろだ！
Kakashi!
カカシ！
My eye...!
おい　カカシ　大丈夫か？
Hey, Kakashi! Are you all right?!
（タイセキ）たとえ　ガキ相手とはいえ
用心にこしたことはねえ。
Even if he's just a kid,
it doesn't hurt to be cautious.
I'll take it nice and slow.
じっくりいくか。
敵のヤツ　やり手だよ。
Our enemy... He's good.
俺の血のついたクナイは
ちゃんと捨ててやがる。
He threw away the kunai knife
stained with the smell of my blood.
また目にゴミでも入ったのかよ。
Don't tell me you got dust
in your eye again?
忍が泣くなっての。
A ninja shouldn't cry...
(まだ死んだわけじゃない))
I'm not dead yet.
((今だったら
カカシをあんな目には…))
If that was now...
I wouldn't have let that
happen to Kakashi...
《タイセキ：死ね！》
Die!
《タイセキ：な　なぜだ…
見えるわけはない》
W-Why... There's no way you could see...
((オビト　お前…。
Obito... You...!
W-What is... that eye?
（タイセキ）な…　何だ　その眼は。
This time... I'll protect my comrade!
ここは…　仲間は俺が守る！
（カッコウ）意外にしぶといヤツだ。
You're surprisingly stubborn.
Hmm.... They're all so pathetic.
どいつもこいつも　だらしねえ。
リンのチャクラの流れが荒れてる。
The flow of Rin's chakra is disturbed...
俺やお前のチャクラの動きと違うぞ。
It's different from your chakra or mine.
おそらく幻術にかけられてる。
She's probably under a genjutsu...
すぐにでも情報を
聞き出そうとしたんだ。
They didn't waste any time trying to
get the information out of her.
一度　手合わせしたが
かなりの早技だ。
We fought him earlier.
He's fast...
(気をつけろ。
おう！))
Stay alert!
Right!
《オビト：そして　今度こそ
仲間を守れる忍に　俺が…》
And...
At last, I'll be a shinobi
who can protect his comrades.
Wake up to reality.
((現実を見ろ。
Nothing ever goes as
planned in this world.
この世は思いどおりには
いかぬことばかりだ。
長く生きれば生きるほど
現実は苦しみと痛みと→
The longer you live,
the more you realize that
only pain, suffering,
and futility exist in this reality.
虚しさだけが
漂っていることに気づく。
《なんだ？　このじじい…》
What's with this old man...?
Listen to me...
いいか　この世のすべてにおいて→
In this world, wherever there is light,
光があたるところには
必ず影がある。
there are always shadows.
As long as there is
a concept of victors,
勝者という概念がある以上
敗者は同じくして存在する。
the vanquished will also exist.
The selfish desire for peace
gives rise to war.
平和を保ちたいとする
利己的な意志が戦争を起こし→
And hatred is born in order
to protect love.
愛を守るために憎しみが生まれる。
These are all nexuses,
これらは因果関係にあり
切り離すことができん　本来はな。
causal relationships that
cannot be separated.
Normally, that is.
The old man's on a roll...
《スイッチ入っちゃってるよ。
Old people ramble forever
once they start.
こうなると
じじいの話は長ぇんだよな》
So... where are we anyway?
で　ここは　どのへんなんだ？
Because you were hurt,
someone else was saved.
お前が傷ついたからこそ
代わりに助かった者がいる。
(違うか？))
Isn't that so?
This is bad!
Run for the exit!
((やばい！
みんな出口に走れ！
うっ！
カカシ！
Kakashi!
（オビト）大丈夫か…　リン　カカシ。
Are you all right?
Rin...? Kakashi...?
Obito!
（カカシ）オビト！
Don't...
やめろ　いいんだ　カカシ。
It's okay, Kakashi.
俺は　もう　ダメみたいだ。
I don't think I can make it...
体の右側は
ほとんど潰れちまって→
My right side is totally crushed.
感覚すらねえ。
I can't even feel anything...
クソッ！
Dammit!
この俺の写輪眼をやるからよ。
I'm giving you... my Sharingan.
里のヤツらが何て言おうと
お前は立派な上忍だ。
Whatever the village may say...
you are... a great jonin.
That's how I really feel...
それが　俺の気持だ。
受け取ってくれ。
So please accept it.
カカシ…　リンを頼むぜ。
Kakashi... Take care of Rin.
Rin, hurry, take my hand!
リン　早くつかまれ！
Rin!
リン！
Obito!
(オビト！))
《カカシのヤツと
せっかく仲よくなれたのに…。
Just when Kakashi and I were...
starting to get along...
リンには結局　告白できなかったな。
I couldn't tell Rin that I... loved her...
みんなと
もっと一緒にいたかった》
I wish... I could've spent more time...
with everyone.
((さっきから　うるせえよ！
Shut up already!
俺は　こんなとこに
長居はしたくねえんだ！
I don't want to stay here long!
さっさと…　ぐっ！
I have to...
Leave if you really want to.
出ていきたければ
出ていくといい。
動ければの話だがな。
If you can move, that is.
Wait a minute...
《待てよ。
これって　おかしいだろ？
There's something weird
about this.
What's an old man with the Sharingan
doing here all by himself?
なんで写輪眼のじじいが
１人でこんなとこにいんだ？
If I think about it,
よく考えてみりゃ→
I know all the geezers and grannies
in the Hidden Leaf Village,
木ノ葉のジジババなら
みんな知ってる　この俺が→
and if I've never seen him around...
一度も見たこともねえ
ってことは…。
It means this guy is currently
not a Leaf Shinobi.
このじじい
今は木ノ葉の忍じゃねえ。
Which means...
つまり…》
Gramps... I bet...
じじい　テメエ抜け忍だな？
you're a Rogue Ninja, aren't you?
Just who are you?!
何者なんだ？
I am... an Uchiha ghost.
俺は　うちはの亡霊。
I am Madara Uchiha.
うちはマダラだ。
M-Madara...?!
《マ…　マダラ？》
By Madara...
マダラって…
俺のご先祖の　うちはマダラか！？
You mean Madara Uchiha,
as in my ancestor?!
That Madara's supposed to
have died ages ago!
マダラなら　とっくに死んでなきゃ
おかしいだろ！
What era are we talking about?!
いつの時代の話だよ！
お前にとって　俺は死神のほうが
まだ信憑性があるか？
So you're more likely to
believe that I'm Death?
I guess I am Death, in a sense...
そうだな　ある意味　死神かもな。
For this reality, truly is hell.
この現実こそ　地獄だ。
I'm a cheater of death who
would be dead in no time...
確かに　俺は後ろの魔像から
チャクラを常に供給し続けなければ→
if I weren't continuously
siphoning chakra
あっという間に死んでしまう
死に損ないだがな。
from that Gedo Statue behind me.
I'm going home!
俺は帰る！
I wouldn't bother.
There are no exits here.
やめておけ。
ここには出口はない。
In any case, neither you
nor I can leave this place.
なによりも　お前も俺も
ここより出ることはできん。
At least, not with our bodies.
この体ではな。
動くと　せっかくくっつけた
柱間の人造体がはがれる。
If you move, the synthetic tissue
of Hashirama
that I went to the trouble of
attaching to you will peel off.
死にたいのか？
Do you want to die?
お前には　今度いろいろと
やってもらいたいことがある。
There are a lot of things
I'd like you to do for me,
for the rest of our lives.
俺と一生な。
I went to great pains to save you.
せっかく助けたのだ　死に急ぐな。
Don't rush to your death.
What do you want?
何が望みだ？
アンタみたいなクソじじいが→
What does a geezer like you want
from a brat like me?!
こんなガキひとり捕まえて
何しようってんだ？
To sever the fate of this world.
この世の因果を断ち切る。
A world of only victors...
勝者だけの世界　平和だけの世界
愛だけの世界→
a world of only peace...
a world of only love.
それらだけの世界をつくる。
I will create such a world.
So what! Who cares!
知るかよ　そんなの！
I just want to go back to everyone!
俺はただ　みんなのところへ
帰りたいだけだ。
I told you, things don't go
as planned.
言ったはずだ。
思いどおりにはいかぬのがここだ。
You will realize that in time.
お前もいずれ気づくことになる。
If you really want to die so badly,
then go ahead.
勝手に死ぬなら　それでもいいが→
But I'll be taking that Sharingan
of yours.
代わりに
その写輪眼はいただくぞ。
Why do you want my eye?!
なんで眼を欲しがる？
You already have
your own Sharingan!
お前はもう
写輪眼を持ってんだろ！
Actually, my original eyes are
on loan to another.
いや…　俺本来の眼は→
他の者に預けてあってな→
This one is a spare
I transplanted later.
この眼は
そのあと移植した余りものだ。
もう少しストックがあってもいい。
I'd like to have a few more in stock...
Since I don't have a right eye yet.
右目がまだ入っていなくてな。
And only with two together can
the Sharingan's true power be unleashed.
(写輪眼は左右揃って
本来の力を発揮するものだ))
Then... that means...
《なら　俺がカカシと揃えば→
If I team up with Kakashi,
we'll both be even stronger.
より強くなれる
ってことじゃねえか。
Then we'll be able to
protect Rin properly, together!
リンを今度こそ　２人でちゃんと
守れるってことじゃねえか。
I definitely can't stay here.
なおさら　ここにはいられねえ。
Just you wait... Kakashi... Rin!
待ってろよ　カカシ　リン！
I'm...
俺は…。
alive!
生きてる！》
I already know
wakatten da yo
it doesn't belong to anyone else
hoka no dare demo nakute
I'll follow all the rainbows in the sky
kono sora ippai no niji wo kakete miseru yo
now matter how much time passes I can never reach it
itsumade tattemo todokanai yo
I keep repeating the same thing every day
ato nankai mo kurikaesu nichijou
I'm chasing a future I once dreamed of
oikaketeru no wa itsuka jibun de egaita mirai
and I was blaming it all on someone else
mata dareka no sei ni shiteta
I already know
wakatten da yo
that I can't go on like this
kono mama ja dame na koto
can I even believe in the "future self" I saw with my own eyes anymore?
kono me de midashita ashita no jibun wa mou shinjite ii n desu ka
I already know
wakatten da yo
that I have to go
ikanakucha ikenai koto
beyond the rainbow there's another future waiting for me
niji no mukou de matteru mou hitotsu no mirai he
Hey, I was just outside and
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
your friends Rin and Stupid Kakashi
are in a real pinch!
美空ひばりです。
What's going on?!
They're by themselves, completely
surrounded by Hidden Mist Shinobi!
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
Kakashi, you promised me!
Please protect Rin!
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート　名曲！
にっぽんの歌』　２時間スペシャル。
I'll be right there!
（松丸）今回も　ご覧の
豪華な歌手の皆さんによる→
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"I'm In Hell"
華麗なステージをお届けいたします。
Kakashi and I will protect Rin!